<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://benswift.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://benswift.me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-03-29T16:32:59+11:00</updated><id>https://benswift.me/feed.xml</id><title type="html">benswift.me</title><subtitle>livecoder &amp; researcher homepage - code, creativity, culture</subtitle><author><name>Ben Swift</name></author><entry><title type="html">The c/c/c studio</title><link href="https://benswift.me/blog/2019/03/20/reimagine-fellow-project-pitch/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The c/c/c studio" /><published>2019-03-20T11:09:00+11:00</published><updated>2019-03-20T11:09:00+11:00</updated><id>https://benswift.me/blog/2019/03/20/reimagine-fellow-project-pitch</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://benswift.me/blog/2019/03/20/reimagine-fellow-project-pitch/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note to readers:&lt;/em&gt; this is my project plan for a &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2019/02/07/reimagining-engineering-cs-at-the-anu/&quot;&gt;Reimagine Fellowship&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;

  &lt;h2&gt;table of contents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#project-background-and-description&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-project-background-and-description&quot;&gt;Project Background and Description&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#project-scope&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-project-scope&quot;&gt;Project Scope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#deliverables&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-deliverables&quot;&gt;Deliverables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#project-sponsor-and-stakeholders&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-project-sponsor-and-stakeholders&quot;&gt;Project Sponsor and Stakeholders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#success-metrics&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-success-metrics&quot;&gt;Success Metrics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#business-readiness&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-business-readiness&quot;&gt;Business Readiness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#key-activities&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-key-activities&quot;&gt;Key Activities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#costtime-commitments&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-costtime-commitments&quot;&gt;Cost/Time Commitments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#risks&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-risks&quot;&gt;Risk, Challenges and Dependencies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#rapid-analysis&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-rapid-analysis&quot;&gt;Rapid Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#notes-for-draft-readers&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-notes-for-draft-readers&quot;&gt;Notes for draft readers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;project-background-and-description&quot;&gt;Project Background and Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;elevator-pitch&quot;&gt;Elevator pitch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;hl-para&quot;&gt;I want to start the &lt;strong&gt;c/c/c studio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:ccc-group&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:ccc-group&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, an extension/outreach program
in creative code (using code to make art + music &amp;amp; other cool things) for ACT
High School&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:hs-college&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:hs-college&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; students interested in the intersection of art &amp;amp;
technology. Students will be part of a weekly on-campus interactive learning
community where they will be guided by instructors in creating their own new
works of code-based art &amp;amp; music. At the end of each semester we will host a
“grad show” gallery exhibition/performance of the works from the c/c/c studio.
This program will attract fantastic students who might otherwise not study
Engineering or Computer Science (either at ANU or elsewhere) and engage the
wider community in helping them &lt;em&gt;reimagine&lt;/em&gt; what it is to be a Computer
Scientist or Engineer in the 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;problems-to-be-addressed&quot;&gt;Problems to be addressed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interest in Computer Science (CS) education is exploding at all educational
levels, but there’s a lack of support for students in schools which don’t have
specialist teachers or an appropriate learning environment—especially for the
“fun” stuff which goes beyond textbook exercises. At the ANU we haven’t done
very much to engage at a pre-tertiary level, mostly because we’re flat-out
dealing with the huge growth in students at a tertiary level. The c/c/c studio
program will address that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, CS still suffers from a stereotype of being for “nerdy white/asian
males”, and those groups are certainly over-represented in our undergraduate CS
cohort compared to other groups. The Reimagine “big tent” CS education
philosophy needs ways of attracting students who don’t fit the usual CS
stereotypes. In attracting &amp;amp; nurturing students who are interested in using
computers in the arts &amp;amp; music the c/c/c studio can be &lt;em&gt;one part&lt;/em&gt; of that bigger
mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Undergraduate students at the ANU can take my &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs.anu.edu.au/courses/comp1720/&quot;&gt;COMP1720: Art &amp;amp; Interaction in
New Media&lt;/a&gt; course as part of a major in
either a CS degree or a Bachelor of Visual Arts (or indeed as a cross-campus
elective in any program). COMP1720 has run successfully as a cross-disciplinary
“learn to code” course for several years. As the &lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt; in STEAM, the arts
provide an important avenue for engaging students with coding and computer
science, especially those who might not normally engage with CS-type activities.
The c/c/c studio will extend this opportunity to High School students in the
ACT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;existing-alternatives&quot;&gt;Existing alternatives&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some ACT High Schools already have great non-traditional/creative CS/IT
programs, for example Dickson College, Radford College, Canberra (Boys) Grammar.
I plan to partner with teachers at these schools as &lt;a href=&quot;#early-adopters&quot;&gt;early
adopters&lt;/a&gt;. However, even in these cases there’s a missing link
once students finish High School—where can they go to further develop their
creative practice? The c/c/c studio program will give them deep links &amp;amp;
relationships into the ANU (across both CS and the Schools of Art &amp;amp; Design and
School of Music) and an avenue for continuing their work in this area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few outreach programs &lt;a href=&quot;https://cecs.anu.edu.au/study/more-information/outreach-programs-schools&quot;&gt;advertised on the CECS
website&lt;/a&gt;,
however the listed programs are dominated by Engineering rather than CS (9 vs 4
programs) and of the 4 CS programs I’m involved with 2 of them already. There’s
also the official &lt;a href=&quot;http://extension.anu.edu.au&quot;&gt;ANU Extension&lt;/a&gt; scheme for Year
11 &amp;amp; 12 students in the ACT, however CS doesn’t yet participate in this scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the wider ANU context, one similar program is the ANU School of Music’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://music.cass.anu.edu.au/open-school&quot;&gt;Open
School of Music&lt;/a&gt;. From their website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The aim of the Open School of Music is to provide developing musicians with a
supportive and nurturing social environment in which they can improve their
technical and theoretical knowledge of music, interact and share their love of
music with their peers, and rub shoulders with the world of professional
music-making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In particular, it aims to ensure that high-quality music education is
accessible to all children in the ACT who have the interest and aptitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2018 I ran the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs.anu.edu.au/code-creativity-culture/projects/laptop-ensemble/&quot;&gt;ANU Laptop
Ensemble&lt;/a&gt;,
which attempted to provide a similar open-ended space for creative exploration
to the c/c/c studio, but for undergraduate students. I will be drawing on all of
these connections &amp;amp; influences in developing the c/c/c studio program during my
Reimagine Fellowship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;project-scope&quot;&gt;Project Scope&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;solution-proposed&quot;&gt;Solution proposed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weekly c/c/c studio sessions won’t be lectures, or even tutorials—they
will adopt the artist’s studio model, with each student working on their own
code-based music or visual artwork as a semester-long creative “work”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first part of this project is to actually figure out the details of how
these workshops will run, but here are some initial plans:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;each session will be small—up to 20 students with 1 instructor (Ben) and one tutor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;students will commit to attending for a semester, with an
exhibition/performance at the end&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;students will apply to participate based on interest and aptitude, so we can
assume that students are engaged and willing to be self-directed in their
learning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;some “training” material may be adapted from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs.anu.edu.au/courses/comp1720/labs/&quot;&gt;COMP1720 lab
material&lt;/a&gt; and tweaked as
appropriate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;students will be exposed to regular guest “provocations” from students and
creative researchers from CECS, the ANU School of Art &amp;amp; Design, ANU School of
Music, ANU Centre for Digital Humanities Research, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;as well as me (Ben) guiding the students, we will employ one of our
undergraduate students as a tutor for these sessions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the weekly c/c/c studio sessions, we will also run (less
frequent) workshops in the High Schools themselves. These workshops will be used
to recruit/excite students with the interest and aptitude to attend the c/c/c
studio program, to share knowledge and open minds to the sorts of things which
are possible with computers and programming, and to strengthen the pathways
between the IT programs in ACT High Schools into our CECS undergraduate programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;value-to-organisationreimagine-strategic-alignment&quot;&gt;Value to organisation/Reimagine strategic alignment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cecs.anu.edu.au/reimagine&quot;&gt;Reimagine Project page&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We will inspire a new generation of high-potential, creative people to come to
engineering and computing with a diverse range of interests, motivations,
perspectives and career aspirations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The c/c/c studio is designed to attract that new generation and to provide them
a supportive community in which to learn, create, and share. More than that, it
aims to unlock the latent potential in students who never knew their diverse
interests (especially in the arts &amp;amp; music) &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; be used in engineering and
computing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The c/c/c studio is also an “outwardly-focused education program” (taken from
the &lt;em&gt;Reimagine Fellow&lt;/em&gt; position description) which builds two-way relationships
with ACT High Schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the c/c/c studio presents an opportunity as an “object lesson” for the
breadth of places that an Engineering/Computer Science skillset can be
applied—a crucial part of Reimagining CECS from a problem-solving to
problem-_finding_ institution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;target-users&quot;&gt;Target users&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ACT High School &amp;amp; College students, as well as students from the wider Canberra
region (since we could do a travelling version of the workshop).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, teachers from these schools will be encouraged to partner with us in both
supporting their students to participate in the c/c/c studio, and also to
incorporate creative arts &amp;amp; code activities in their classrooms in general (e.g.
using the c/c/c studio curriculum, which will be made freely available).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;early-adopters&quot;&gt;Early adopters&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will build on my (and others) existing relationships with teachers from
Dickson College, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.radford.act.edu.au&quot;&gt;Radford College&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://lynehamhs.act.edu.au&quot;&gt;Lyneham
High&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://cgs.act.edu.au&quot;&gt;Canberra (Boys)
Grammar&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cggs.act.edu.au&quot;&gt;Canberra Girls
Grammar&lt;/a&gt;. These schools, with their existing groups
of students interested in creative code, can give early feedback and serve as
“seed” populations for the first semester of c/c/c studio sessions in S1 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;deliverables&quot;&gt;Deliverables&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project will deliver:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;a &lt;strong&gt;curriculum&lt;/strong&gt; (including instructor notes) for the weekly c/c/c studio
sessions, which will be freely released to the public under a creative commons
licence (&lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&quot;&gt;CC BY-NC-SA&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;a biannual &lt;strong&gt;c/c/c studio grad show&lt;/strong&gt; gallery exhibition and music performance
held on campus (perhaps in the new cultural centre) as the capstone for each
semester’s student work in the c/c/c studio&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’ll be lots of other stuff, too: building a community of practice,
deepening ANU CS/CECS’s relationships with ACT High Schools, giving our
undergraduate students a chance to mentor these high school students, etc. But
that’s intangible stuff, so I’m not sure if they count as a deliverables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;project-sponsor-and-stakeholders&quot;&gt;Project Sponsor and Stakeholders&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sponsor&lt;/strong&gt;: Nick?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Owner&lt;/strong&gt;: Ben Swift&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consultations&lt;/strong&gt;:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://researchers.anu.edu.au/researchers/hunter-at&quot;&gt;Alec Hunter&lt;/a&gt; (ANU
SoM, previously the convenor of the Open School of Music program)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://researchers.anu.edu.au/researchers/hinchcliffe-gb&quot;&gt;Geoff
Hinchcliffe&lt;/a&gt; (ANU
School of Art &amp;amp; Design)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cecs.anu.edu.au/people/qing-wang&quot;&gt;Qing Wang&lt;/a&gt; (RSCS Associate
Director of Education Partnerships)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cecs.anu.edu.au/people/tony-hosking&quot;&gt;Tony Hosking&lt;/a&gt; (RSCS Director)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anu.edu.au/news/all-news/anu-spaces-–-dr-liz-williams&quot;&gt;Liz
Williams&lt;/a&gt;
(3Ai Institute) (or perhaps someone else from 3Ai)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;success-metrics&quot;&gt;Success Metrics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will judge the success of this program using the following metrics, both in
absolute terms and also trends over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participation&lt;/strong&gt;: how many students participate?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Retention&lt;/strong&gt;: for the weekly c/c/c studio sessions, do students keep coming
over time?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creative outputs&lt;/strong&gt;: we’ll have an end-of-semester concert and gallery
show—are the things the students are making any good?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Curriculum uptake&lt;/strong&gt;: is the curriculum developed for the c/c/c studio
sessions used by HS teachers to run similar groups in their schools?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;business-readiness&quot;&gt;Business Readiness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;physical-space-requirements&quot;&gt;Physical space requirements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The c/c/c studio will require a room for one 2-3 hour session every week in an
after-school friendly timeslot (perhaps 4pm-6pm). This room needs to have one
computer per student (either a lab machine or personal laptop) which can run a
modern web browser (Chrome, Firefox, Safari). One of our computer labs in
Building #145 should do the job initially.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, some sound gear may be required for the students interested in
making music, e.g. headphones &amp;amp; a small mixing desk (I have some of this gear
already).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;enrolmentadmin-requirements&quot;&gt;Enrolment/admin requirements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the short term, it would be great to be able to give students who complete
the c/c/c studio program (which will be held in semester-long increments) an
official ANU certificate of completion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Longer-term, it’d be really great to have the ability to give participants in
the c/c/c studio program credit into our first-year CS program (e.g.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://cs.anu.edu.au/courses/comp1720/&quot;&gt;COMP1720&lt;/a&gt;) if they decide to come and
study in CECS. This is the same as the equivalent &lt;a href=&quot;http://extension.anu.edu.au/study/discovering-engineering&quot;&gt;Discovering Engineering
extension program&lt;/a&gt;,
which (I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt;) gives students credit for a first-year ENGN course if they
study Engineering at the ANU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will require public liability insurance for any students who come onto campus for the c/c/c
studio sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;key-activities&quot;&gt;Key Activities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;What?&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Who?&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;By when?&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;develop relationships with High Schools&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ben&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;end 2019&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;create curriculum&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ben&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;end 2019&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;weekly c/c/c studio sessions&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ben + tutor(s)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ongoing (beginning 2020)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;in-HS workshops&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ben + tutor(s)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ongoing (beginning 2020)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;c/c/c studio grad show&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;students&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;end of semester (beginning mid-2020)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;costtime-commitments&quot;&gt;Cost/Time Commitments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ben&lt;/strong&gt;: 2 days/week (40% FTE) for 2.5 years (mid 2019-end 2021). This includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;developing the curriculum&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;building relationships with High Schools and recruiting students&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;delivering the weekly c/c/c studio session&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;running workshops in High Schools (perhaps once a month)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tutors&lt;/strong&gt;: depending on how many students attend, it’d be great to be able to
employ one (or more) of our undergraduate students to help support the students
in the c/c/c studio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Equipment&lt;/strong&gt;: music gear (~2k) so that students can connect their laptops to
play &lt;em&gt;together&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grad show budget&lt;/strong&gt;: (~1k per semester from 2020) for venue/equipment hire
(e.g. PA, fancy projectors, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Estimated project costs&lt;/strong&gt;: TBD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;risks&quot;&gt;Risk, Challenges and Dependencies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Risk&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Who’s accountable?&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Mitigation steps&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;When?&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;students don’t turn up&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ben&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;get buy-in from &lt;a href=&quot;#early-adopters&quot;&gt;early adopter schools&lt;/a&gt; who are already running this sort of thing&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ongoing&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;c/c/c studio doesn’t meet the requirements for official &lt;a href=&quot;http://extension.anu.edu.au&quot;&gt;ANU Extension&lt;/a&gt; accreditation&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ben, CECS education committee&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;talk to &lt;em&gt;Discovering Engineering&lt;/em&gt; people, and if it doesn’t work it’s no big deal&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2020&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ANU arts &amp;amp; music folks feel like we’re treading on their turf&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ben&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;build on existing cross-campus relationships—keep them in the loop&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2019&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;too many students&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ben&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;introduce some sort of portfolio-based admissions procedure, get ANU UG students to share the teaching load&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2020+&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;students have wide range of different abilities/familiarity with the material&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ben, tutors&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;keep class sizes small so we can tailor material to each student, encourage peer-assisted learning at the different stages&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2020&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;project relies too much on Ben’s particular mix of skills and interests&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ben, others&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;get other like-minded folks from inside CECS and across campus involved, train up other CECS people (e.g. tutors) to share the workload&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2019&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rapid-analysis&quot;&gt;Rapid Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who&lt;/em&gt;—who is undertaking this role?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;What&lt;/em&gt;—what are they being asked to do?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When&lt;/em&gt;—when will their role be completed?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;ecommend&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;gree&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P&lt;/strong&gt;erform&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;nput&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;ecide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This section TODO; see note below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes-for-draft-readers&quot;&gt;Notes for draft readers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It’s currently a CS pitch—there’s not much involvement from the Engineering
schools at present, although this could change in the future. But I’ve decided
to start with what I know.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Looking at the &lt;a href=&quot;#risks&quot;&gt;Risks&lt;/a&gt; section, a lot of it’s on my shoulders—need
to fix that.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The project proposal part isn’t super detailed, and that’s mostly because I
need to do some research (discussions with HS teachers, read literature &amp;amp;
examine similar programs elsewhere) in the first 6months (mid-late 2019) to
figure out those details.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This isn’t exactly what I’d put in my &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2019/02/07/reimagining-engineering-cs-at-the-anu/&quot;&gt;original pitch&lt;/a&gt;, but from
discussions in our workshop the other day I think this outreach project hits
one of the main goals of the Reimagine project, and is really complementary to
the other Fellows’ projects.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Some of the nomenclature is still TBC, e.g. the whole “c/c/c studio” thing,
code vs tech, art vs music vs creativity, etc. Part of the initial phase of
the project will be workshopping these terms to see which ones best resonate
with the potential audiences, and also which best capture what &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; goes
on.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I’m not sure about the &lt;a href=&quot;#rapid-analysis&quot;&gt;RAPID&lt;/a&gt; part, I’m open to suggestions
on what that section might mean in the context of this project.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It’s really hard to have all the necessary stakeholder conversations while I’m
on parental leave. So while I’ve discussed this sort of thing to varying
degrees with everyone concerned (i.e. I’m sure no-one would be &lt;em&gt;shocked&lt;/em&gt; to
hear this project pitch) there’s a chance that some of the details will change
as I make things more concrete and sort out the details.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:ccc-group&quot;&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;named after the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://cs.anu.edu.au/code-creativity-culture/&quot;&gt;code/creativity/culture&lt;/a&gt;
(c/c/c) research group that I lead, which already has some name recognition
around the place and will be useful for “branding” this activity &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:ccc-group&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:hs-college&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;since we’re in the ACT, I mean Hign School &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; College (i.e. years 7–12) &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:hs-college&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Swift</name></author><category term="reimagine" /><category term="teaching" /><category term="research" /><summary type="html">Note to readers: this is my project plan for a Reimagine Fellowship.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mapping over table rows in org-mode</title><link href="https://benswift.me/blog/2019/03/09/mapping-over-table-rows-in-org-mode/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mapping over table rows in org-mode" /><published>2019-03-09T19:53:00+11:00</published><updated>2019-03-09T19:53:00+11:00</updated><id>https://benswift.me/blog/2019/03/09/mapping-over-table-rows-in-org-mode</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://benswift.me/blog/2019/03/09/mapping-over-table-rows-in-org-mode/">&lt;p&gt;I’m an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/&quot;&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt; guy, and so if I’ve got some
simple tabular data I’d &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; rather keep it in an
&lt;a href=&quot;https://orgmode.org&quot;&gt;org-mode&lt;/a&gt; table than have to fire up Excel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- note: the language specifiers for the code blocks in this post are wrong, but they're the &quot;best fit&quot; --&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot;&gt;#+NAME: pap-table
| first name  | last name | yearly-income |
|-------------|-----------|---------------|
| Mr          | Bennett   |          2000 |
| Fitzwilliam | Darcy     |         10000 |
| Charles     | Bingley   |          5000 |
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the prospect of having to keep all those &lt;code&gt;|&lt;/code&gt; characters manually aligned is
freaking you out, don’t worry—&lt;code&gt;orgtbl-mode&lt;/code&gt; does it all for you automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I often want to get my functional programming on and apply a function to
all the rows of the table. Org-mode does have some special syntax with bunch of
cool features for doing arithmetic on the cells (just like Excel formulas) but
I’m usually happier just writing regular elisp to get the job done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nicest&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:nicer&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:nicer&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; way I’ve found to do this is to give the table a &lt;strong&gt;name&lt;/strong&gt; (in
the example above the table name is &lt;code&gt;pap-table&lt;/code&gt;—can you guess why?). Then, you
can tell an elisp &lt;a href=&quot;https://orgmode.org/manual/Structure-of-code-blocks.html&quot;&gt;code
block&lt;/a&gt; about the data
in that table like so (note the &lt;code&gt;:var table=pap-table&lt;/code&gt; at the start):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-scheme&quot;&gt;#+BEGIN_SRC emacs-lisp :var table=pap-table
  (-map
   (lambda (row)
     (cl-destructuring-bind (first last income) row
       (list
        (format &quot;Mr. %s is a man of %s fortune; %s a year.&quot;
                last
                (if (&amp;lt; income 2500) &quot;small&quot; &quot;large&quot;)
                income))))
   table)
#+END_SRC
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, when you evaluate the code block with &lt;code&gt;C-c C-c&lt;/code&gt; (or just &lt;code&gt;, ,&lt;/code&gt; in
Spacemacs) it’ll return the “result”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot;&gt;#+RESULTS:
| Mr. Bennett is a man of small fortune; 2000 a year. |
| Mr. Darcy is a man of large fortune; 10000 a year.  |
| Mr. Bingley is a man of large fortune; 5000 a year. |
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is really handy, as you can imagine. I use it for all sorts of things,
including sending “mail merge” emails with template values (since I also use
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.djcbsoftware.nl/code/mu/mu4e.html&quot;&gt;Emacs as my mail
client&lt;/a&gt;—sending an email is
just an elisp function call away).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;caveats&quot;&gt;Caveats&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few “tricks” in the above process which took me a while to figure
out, so hopefully by listing them here I can save others a bunch of time &amp;amp;
hassle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The elisp doesn’t actually know about the column names from the table—I had
to re-bind them in the code block using &lt;code&gt;cl-destructuring-bind&lt;/code&gt;. Make sure you
change the bindings if you change the names/order of the columns in the table!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Org-mode tables don’t have a way of specifying the column “type”, so while
it’ll try it’s best with the basics (e.g. detecting strings vs numbers)
sometimes it gets confused. It’s probably worth putting an explicit e.g.
&lt;code&gt;string-to-number&lt;/code&gt; in if you want to be sure.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the example above my elisp block returns a value (a list, since I’m using
&lt;code&gt;-map&lt;/code&gt; from the excellent &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/magnars/dash.el&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;dash.el&lt;/code&gt;
library&lt;/a&gt;) and that’s why the results get
nicely formatted in the results block. If your code is side-effectful but
doesn’t return a value then you see the results in that place, you’ll have to
look elsewhere (e.g. if you call &lt;code&gt;message&lt;/code&gt; you’ll need to look in the
&lt;code&gt;*Messages*&lt;/code&gt; buffer as usual).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Further to the previous caveat, you’ll notice that I’m actually wrapping the
result of the inner &lt;code&gt;lambda&lt;/code&gt; in another &lt;code&gt;list&lt;/code&gt;, so the output of the code
block is actually a list of lists. I could have just returned a list of the
strings, but then it would be interpreted as an &lt;em&gt;1×n&lt;/em&gt; table, rather than the
(nicer looking on the page) &lt;em&gt;n×1&lt;/em&gt; table shown above.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:nicer&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;if there’s a nicer way, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/benswift&quot;&gt;let me know&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:nicer&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Swift</name></author><category term="emacs" /><summary type="html">I’m an Emacs guy, and so if I’ve got some simple tabular data I’d much rather keep it in an org-mode table than have to fire up Excel.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On parental leave and auto-reply messages</title><link href="https://benswift.me/blog/2019/02/26/on-parental-leave-and-auto-reply-messages/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On parental leave and auto-reply messages" /><published>2019-02-26T18:08:00+11:00</published><updated>2019-02-26T18:08:00+11:00</updated><id>https://benswift.me/blog/2019/02/26/on-parental-leave-and-auto-reply-messages</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://benswift.me/blog/2019/02/26/on-parental-leave-and-auto-reply-messages/">&lt;p&gt;I’m now (as of the date of this blog post) on parental leave (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anu.edu.au/news/all-news/anu-announces-major-expansion-of-parental-leave&quot;&gt;thanks,
Brian&lt;/a&gt;
😊). I’m about to set up an email auto-reply which will guard my work email
address until 15 July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;baby dogs - puppies, in fact&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/nathalie-spehner-1338356-unsplash-101dcbae4256574fb70b4f5f00843cfc5a47e6b83c6a51ffb475136ed422d33e.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: the baby I am taking care of is a human baby, but the above photo
contains baby dogs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;hl-para&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s the deal&lt;/strong&gt;: I’m away for a long time, and when I get back in July I’m
going to delete all the unread emails in my inbox. Sorry if that seems harsh,
but it’s the only way to deal with this situation and have any chance of
enjoying one’s return to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you’ve got important information which needs to be actioned &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; July
15, then you need to make alternative arrangements. I wish you all the best,
but I can’t help you out with making it happen.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you’ve got important information which has an expiry date &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; July 15,
then put a note in your calendar to re-email me after that date (because your
email still won’t survive the purge, sorry).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you need to get in touch urgently, then you probably have my personal email
or phone number.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you want to organise some sort of hangs/see baby pictures, then try me on
my personal email or phone number. I will be pushing a pram around campus at
times, and I’d be keen to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But doesn’t that mean you’ll (1) miss a bunch of fantastic opportunities and
(2) let a bunch of folks down?&lt;/em&gt; Well, maybe. On the first point, I already feel
overwhelmed (at times) by the amount of stuff on my to-do list, so any attrition
which occurs is actually kindof appealing. And on the second point I’ve tried
really hard this last month to hand various things over to capable folks, so I’m
hoping that if we are/were working on something then we’ve made a contingency
plan (and that this hasn’t caught you by surprise).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I’m gonna go be a Dad for a while. I’ll still read the odd book, and
maybe even make some more music, but this isn’t a research fellowship—it’s
parental leave. Have a great Autumn/Winter, and I’ll see you on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;p.s.&lt;/em&gt; I really like the title of this post; inhabiting the liminal space
between the the plainspoken declaration “I’m on parental leave” and the more
philosophical (and pretentious) “On &lt;em&gt;blah…&lt;/em&gt;” literary device.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Swift</name></author><category term="life" /><summary type="html">I’m now (as of the date of this blog post) on parental leave (thanks, Brian 😊). I’m about to set up an email auto-reply which will guard my work email address until 15 July.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A dynamic Reimagine logo</title><link href="https://benswift.me/blog/2019/02/21/dynamic-reimagine-logo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A dynamic Reimagine logo" /><published>2019-02-21T10:36:00+11:00</published><updated>2019-02-21T10:36:00+11:00</updated><id>https://benswift.me/blog/2019/02/21/dynamic-reimagine-logo</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://benswift.me/blog/2019/02/21/dynamic-reimagine-logo/">&lt;p&gt;I keep harping on about the &lt;strong&gt;Reimagine project&lt;/strong&gt; because I’m super pumped
about what it means for the way we do Engineering Computer Science here at the
ANU (see &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/pdf/reimagine-fellow-PD.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&quot;https://cecs.anu.edu.au/reimagine&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for more info).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reimagine branding is starting to go up around campus, so I decided to put
together an interactive version of the logo (because giant vinyl prints are
cool, but they don’t spin on mouse-over).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s made with &lt;a href=&quot;https://clojurescript.org&quot;&gt;clojurescript&lt;/a&gt; using
&lt;a href=&quot;https://reagent-project.github.io&quot;&gt;Reagent&lt;/a&gt;, and as always on my blog you can
look at the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/benswift/benswift.github.io/blob/source/_cljs/reimagine_logo/src/reimagine_logo/core.cljs&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;
to see how it works. If you want to really immerse yourself in the thing,
there’s a fullsreen version &lt;a href=&quot;/widgets/reimagine-logo/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;position:relative;padding-top:100%;margin:0;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&quot;/widgets/reimagine-logo/&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to use this logo yourself in some other page, you could use an
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;iframe&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div style=&quot;position:relative;padding-top:100%;margin:0;&quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;iframe
    src=&quot;https://benswift.me/widgets/reimagine-logo/&quot;
    frameborder=&quot;0&quot;
    style=&quot;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;&quot;
  &amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Swift</name></author><category term="widgets" /><category term="reimagine" /><category term="web" /><summary type="html">I keep harping on about the Reimagine project because I’m super pumped about what it means for the way we do Engineering Computer Science here at the ANU (see here and here for more info).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Algorithmic uni marketing billboards</title><link href="https://benswift.me/blog/2019/02/16/algorithmic-uni-marketing-billboards/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Algorithmic uni marketing billboards" /><published>2019-02-16T14:46:00+11:00</published><updated>2019-02-16T14:46:00+11:00</updated><id>https://benswift.me/blog/2019/02/16/algorithmic-uni-marketing-billboards</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://benswift.me/blog/2019/02/16/algorithmic-uni-marketing-billboards/">&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of Murdoch University’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.campaignbrief.com/wa/2017/07/murdoch-university-launches-fr.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;free your
think&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
marketing campaign, I’ve put together a dynamic full-page ad billboard as my
pitch for the ANU’s next marketing campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;hl-para&quot;&gt;Disclaimer: this is in no way an official ANU campaign. Seriously, though, it’s
a great uni—and you should come &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anu.edu.au/study&quot;&gt;study with us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The campaign is called: &lt;strong&gt;verb&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;verb&lt;/strong&gt;—hit refresh to see the
different options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;position:relative;padding-top:56.25%;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&quot;/widgets/algorithmic-ad-billboards/&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to see it in fullscreen, you can &lt;a href=&quot;/widgets/algorithmic-ad-billboards/&quot;&gt;do that as
well&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-it-work&quot;&gt;How does it work?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It uses the same &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js/&quot;&gt;reveal.js&lt;/a&gt; template
that I use for all my &lt;a href=&quot;/talks/index.html&quot;&gt;talks/slides&lt;/a&gt;—it’s basically a one-slide presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each time the page loads, it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pulls a random background image from &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com&quot;&gt;unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;chooses two verbs at random from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.talkenglish.com/vocabulary/top-1000-verbs.aspx&quot;&gt;a list of the 1000 most frequently used
verbs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;places them on the billboard in the form &lt;strong&gt;verb&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;verb&lt;/strong&gt;,
randomising the location and text style&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all things on this blog, you can check out the source to see all the
details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE 12 March&lt;/strong&gt;: I rewrote the billboard code from vanilla js to
&lt;a href=&quot;https://clojurescript.org&quot;&gt;clojurescript&lt;/a&gt; because it makes me happy (source
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/benswift/benswift.github.io/blob/source/_cljs/algorithmic_billboard/src/algorithmic_billboard/core.cljs&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;,
and you can still see the original js source
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/benswift/benswift.github.io/blob/9f4dbeceb99a43f1430593f89bdde68e1fc5c3e9/widgets/algorithmic-ad-billboards.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Swift</name></author><category term="widgets" /><category term="web" /><summary type="html">In the spirit of Murdoch University’s free your think marketing campaign, I’ve put together a dynamic full-page ad billboard as my pitch for the ANU’s next marketing campaign.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reimagining Engineering &amp;amp; CS at the ANU</title><link href="https://benswift.me/blog/2019/02/07/reimagining-engineering-cs-at-the-anu/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reimagining Engineering &amp; CS at the ANU" /><published>2019-02-07T11:55:00+11:00</published><updated>2019-02-07T11:55:00+11:00</updated><id>https://benswift.me/blog/2019/02/07/reimagining-engineering-cs-at-the-anu</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://benswift.me/blog/2019/02/07/reimagining-engineering-cs-at-the-anu/">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://cecs.anu.edu.au&quot;&gt;ANU College of Engineering and Computer Science&lt;/a&gt;
(CECS) is being &lt;em&gt;Reimagined&lt;/em&gt;. Don’t take my word for it; listen to our fearless
leader &lt;a href=&quot;https://cecs.anu.edu.au&quot;&gt;Elanor&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width:100%; margin: 0px auto;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div style=&quot;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0px;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;iframe style=&quot;position: absolute; top: 0px; left: 0px; width: 100%; height: 100%;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FjlgEZzaL6k&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;/iframe&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, this &lt;a href=&quot;https://cecs.anu.edu.au/reimagine&quot;&gt;Reimagine project&lt;/a&gt; is a
&lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; investment from the ANU for CECS to grow, change, and to skate to where
the puck is going to be in 2050 (technologically, societally, culturally, and
more).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The search is on within CECS to identify &lt;strong&gt;Reimagine Fellows&lt;/strong&gt; to champion
various parts of this transformation. This is super-exciting, especially for
interdisciplinary art/design/technology folks (like me). It’d be exciting if it
was happening &lt;em&gt;anywhere&lt;/em&gt;, but it’s particularly exciting that it’s happening
where I am and that I might get a voice in shaping exactly what a “reimagined
CECS” looks like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;hl-para&quot;&gt;Elanor, if you’re reading, I want to be a Reimagine Fellow. And since the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://cecs.anu.edu.au/staff/project-reimagine-fellows-expression-interest&quot;&gt;EoI&lt;/a&gt;
asked for “1000 words &lt;strong&gt;in any format you like&lt;/strong&gt;”, here’s mine in the form of an
FAQ&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:faq&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:faq&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bens-reimagine-fellow-application-faq&quot;&gt;Ben’s &lt;em&gt;Reimagine Fellow&lt;/em&gt; Application FAQ&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-one-sentence-why-do-you-want-to-be-a-reimagine-fellow&quot;&gt;In one sentence, why do you want to be a Reimagine Fellow?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to see more art&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:art&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:art&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; happening in CECS; and I want to strengthen our
education and research ties to the Schools of Art &amp;amp; Design, Music, and Digital
Humanities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-does-that-have-to-do-with-the-reimagine-project&quot;&gt;What does that have to do with the Reimagine Project?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The role of an artist is to ask questions, not to answer them&lt;/em&gt; -&lt;strong&gt;Anton
Chekhov&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Elanor says in the video above, we don’t even know what tomorrow’s problems
are yet; so we need problem &lt;em&gt;finders&lt;/em&gt;, not just problem &lt;em&gt;solvers&lt;/em&gt;. Art and
artists have a key role to play in this (just ask Chekov).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-are-you-the-best-person-to-do-this&quot;&gt;Why are you the best person to do this?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve made a career (so far) of deploying my technical/CS skills to artistic
ends: in my livecoding (both building
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/digego/extempore&quot;&gt;tools&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/livecoding/index.html&quot;&gt;doing live
gigs&lt;/a&gt;), in starting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs.anu.edu.au/code-creativity-culture/projects/laptop-ensemble/&quot;&gt;ANU Laptop
Ensemble&lt;/a&gt;,
in teaching our first-year art+code course
&lt;a href=&quot;https://cs.anu.edu.au/courses/comp1720/&quot;&gt;COMP1720&lt;/a&gt;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the way I’ve built strong networks in these areas across the ANU campus
and in the wider community, and I’ve always said that I was keen to engage with
them more deeply—this is my chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-youre-just-trying-to-score-a-grant-to-go-off-and-do-your-own-weird-art-thing&quot;&gt;So you’re just trying to score a grant to go off and do your own weird art thing?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Absolutely not. Being a Reimagine Fellow isn’t about doing something by
yourself—it’s way too big a project for that. It’s about weaving something
into the whole College&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:dna&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:dna&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, so that by 2050 it affects the way &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt;
thinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-might-this-look-like-concretely&quot;&gt;What might this look like, concretely?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reimagine Project is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Hairy_Audacious_Goal&quot;&gt;big, hairy, and
audacious&lt;/a&gt;, so it’s
difficult to sketch out a detailed description or org chart. However, here are a
few ideas about what it might look like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;in-the-short-term&quot;&gt;In the short term…&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;a CECS-supported “Reimagine residency” (starting asap!) to support artists to
get involved and help us figure out what a Reimagined CECS looks like&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;a new code/creativity/culture major (at both undergraduate and masters level)
where students take courses from within CECS, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://soad.cass.anu.edu.au&quot;&gt;ANU School of Art &amp;amp;
Design&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://music.anu.edu.au&quot;&gt;ANU School of
Music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;new courses within CECS on e.g. algorithmic music composition, creative
making, AI/Deep Learning Art, subversive computing/&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washington.edu/news/2018/05/21/designed-for-evil/&quot;&gt;designing for
evil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:genevieve&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:genevieve&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;more PhD students doing practice-led research on interdisciplinary
art/CS/engineering projects&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;encouraging &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; CECS academics to engage with their peers and the wider
world by &lt;em&gt;making and exhibiting beautiful/interesting/challenging things&lt;/em&gt;, not
just through journal papers&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;in-the-mediumlong-term&quot;&gt;In the medium/long term…&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;a centre of excellence for digital arts/music/multimedia research, teaching
and creative practice (co-hosted by CECS and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://cass.anu.edu.au&quot;&gt;College of Arts &amp;amp; Social
Sciences&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;a thoroughly non-traditional project-based “creative tech” masters program,
with no classes, no heirarchies, just a bunch of brilliant students set loose
with duct tape, gaming GPUs, a giant bag of sensors &amp;amp; actuators, soldering
irons, a 3D printer, oh my. (Geoff Hinchcliffe and I have discussed
this—we’re both thrilled and terrified at the prospect. And I love what the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://3ainstitute.cecs.anu.edu.au/#apply&quot;&gt;3AI&lt;/a&gt; master’s program is shaping
up to be, and am keen to be a part of it.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;incorporating into every course&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:every-course&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:every-course&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; the option to create and submit
a “creative work” to demonstrate attainment of the learning outcomes (🤔
really Ben?)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also look forward to having the time to think through what a deeply artistic
CECS looks like. I’m sure that in collaboration with the other Reimagine Fellows
and the rest of the design team we can come up even more ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-does-this-further-the-broader-goals-of-the-reimagine-project&quot;&gt;How does this further the broader goals of the Reimagine Project…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;in-research&quot;&gt;…in research?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artists have always been at the vanguard of building new things (or seeing/using
old things in new ways). If an artist has an idea in their head for what they
want to create, but the tools to realise it don’t exist yet, that artist is
&lt;em&gt;intrinsically&lt;/em&gt; motivated to figure out how to make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also want to be clear that my pitch here isn’t to view the arts as a technical
problem that needs to be &lt;em&gt;solved&lt;/em&gt; by engineers and computer scientists: “hey
artists, thanks for the last few thousand years, we’ll take it from here”. We’ve
already got too much technochauvinism in tech. Instead, the pitch is that a
newly-Reimagined CECS can &lt;em&gt;include&lt;/em&gt; artists in shaping what the computer
scientists and engineers of 2050 look like, so that it’s &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; an “us and them”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the top research institutions in the world are asking real questions in
the fields of creative technology, digital art, music and design: have a look at
&lt;a href=&quot;#where-in-the-world-is-this-already-happening&quot;&gt;the list below&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;in-education&quot;&gt;…in education?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That Chekov quote above really nails it. For some students, being asked to make
something creative/artistic is what it takes to flick the switch to go beyond
the “what boxes do I need to tick for me to get a P/CR/D/HD” mindset to actually
asking the right questions. I see this sometimes in
&lt;a href=&quot;https://cs.anu.edu.au/courses/comp1720/&quot;&gt;COMP1720&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s one of the most
enjoyable things about teaching that course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More broadly, I want to see more dreamers, doodlers and “creatives”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:creatives&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:creatives&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
study engineering or CS at uni. Too often they feel like they have to choose
between “pursuing the dream” or selling out and studying something boring &amp;amp;
pragmatic, and I fear that we (CECS) miss out on some &lt;em&gt;brilliant&lt;/em&gt; students
because of this. I want these students to know that they can pursue their
creative dreams, and in doing so they’ll be doing top-class
engineering/CS/design work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;in-outreach&quot;&gt;…in outreach?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of my &lt;a href=&quot;/livecoding/index.html&quot;&gt;livecoding&lt;/a&gt; I get
asked to do outreach stuff all the time (you’re welcome, CECS marketing team
😉). I know why I get asked: DJing with code is so &lt;em&gt;different&lt;/em&gt;, it’s a great
hook for engaging folks who might not have thought that combining code &amp;amp; musical
creativity in that way was possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;in-culture&quot;&gt;…in culture?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reimagine Project isn’t just about doing the same things under a different
org-chart. It’s about changing the culture of Engineering &amp;amp; Computing research
and practice. While the stereotypes about nerdy engineers and computer types
isn’t necessarily fair in my experience, there’s no smoke without a fire, and
there &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; some things we need to do better. Incorporating the arts and
creative expression deep within our education, research and outreach work will
change the way we communicate with the outside world, but it’ll also change the
sorts of people we attract, and welcoming new perspectives into CECS is another
way we can enact cultural change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;isnt-this-treading-on-the-toes-of-the-school-of-art--design-and-the-school-of-music-and-&quot;&gt;Isn’t this treading on the toes of the School of Art &amp;amp; Design (and the School of Music, and …)?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No—in fact we need to work with our colleagues in those places to make this
stuff happen. I already co-supervise PhD students with
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mtchl&quot;&gt;Mitchell&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gravitron&quot;&gt;Geoff&lt;/a&gt;
from the School or Art &amp;amp; Design, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tmtn&quot;&gt;Terhi&lt;/a&gt; from the
Centre for Digital Humanities Research, and I run the ANU Laptop Ensemble with
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/huntercomposer&quot;&gt;Alec&lt;/a&gt; from the School of Music. And I want
to see &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; of this type of cross-supervision across these parts of campus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, this “treading on toes” question looms over the whole Reimagine
Project. I think the best way forward is to partner with the other parts of
campus to bring their expertise and smoosh it together with ours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concretely, that means:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sending CECS coursework students to take courses in other parts of campus (as
part of majors/minors/electives, etc.) as well as the other way around&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;co-employing academics across Colleges in joint positions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;increasing our to participation in the ANU’s interdisciplinary HDR programs
like &lt;a href=&quot;http://rsha.cass.anu.edu.au/students/future/iccr&quot;&gt;ICCR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-in-the-world-is-this-already-happening&quot;&gt;Where in the world is this already happening?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a few places, including what each place says about their goals (from the
marketing copy on their own website). Many (but not all) of these labs/groups
are in CS/Engineering Schools, or at least in design schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.media.mit.edu&quot;&gt;MIT Media Lab&lt;/a&gt; is an interdisciplinary
research lab that encourages the unconventional mixing and matching of
seemingly disparate research areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://studioforcreativeinquiry.org&quot;&gt;Frank-Ratchye STUDIO for Creative
Inquiry&lt;/a&gt; at Carnegie Mellon University is
a laboratory for atypical, anti-disciplinary, and inter-institutional research
at the intersections of arts, science, technology and culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sensilab.monash.edu&quot;&gt;SensiLab&lt;/a&gt; is a technology-driven, design-focused
research lab based at Monash University in Melbourne, Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;NYU’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://tisch.nyu.edu/itp&quot;&gt;ITP&lt;/a&gt; (Interactive Telecommunications
Program) is a two-year graduate program located in the Tisch School of the
Arts whose mission is to explore the imaginative use of communications
technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://c4dm.eecs.qmul.ac.uk&quot;&gt;Centre for Digital Music (c4dm)&lt;/a&gt; at Queen
Mary University of London is a world-leading multidisciplinary research group
in the field of Music &amp;amp; Audio Technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://eavi.goldsmithsdigital.com&quot;&gt;Embodied AudioVisual Interaction
(EAVI)&lt;/a&gt; group at Goldsmiths is a research
group focused on embodied interaction with sound and image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Stanford &lt;a href=&quot;(https://ccrma.stanford.edu)&quot;&gt;Center for Computer Research in Music and
Acoustics&lt;/a&gt; (CCRMA) is a multi-disciplinary
facility where composers and researchers work together using computer-based
technology both as an artistic medium and as a research tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://sfpc.io&quot;&gt;School for Poetic Computation&lt;/a&gt; is an artist run school in
New York that was founded in 2013. A small group of students and faculty work
closely to explore the intersections of code, design, hardware and theory —
focusing especially on artistic intervention. It’s a hybrid of a school,
residency and research group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://anclab.org/joinus/&quot;&gt;Arts and Creativity Lab&lt;/a&gt; at the National
University of Singapore provides an environment for arts-driven research and
technology development, as well as artistic practice and experimentation
related to scientific research methods and results&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;has-the-anu-ever-had-anything-like-this-before&quot;&gt;Has the ANU ever had anything like this before?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, for example &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.avatar.com.au/courses/acat/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, and it was
amazing. The story about why ACAT is no longer around is long, and I’ve only
really ever heard it second/third-hand, and I’m not proposing to resurrect ACAT
as part of the Reimagine Project. But it’s important to know one’s history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sounds-like-a-huge-job-benhow-are-you-going-to-manage-it&quot;&gt;Sounds like a huge job, Ben—how are you going to manage it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not on my own, that’s for sure. Only by building up our capacity in these areas.
As an example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cpmpercussion&quot;&gt;Dr. Charles Martin&lt;/a&gt; is just
about to start as a new Lecturer in RSCS, and he’s a computer musician (apps and
ML for group musical improvisation). The campus also has many other
interdisciplinary artists who have been hiding their lights under bushels—I
want to give them a banner to rally to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to think big, and I look forward to a day where there’s a long list of
academic staff &amp;amp; PhD students exploring new avenues for technologically and
culturally sophisticated artistic practice within CECS and the broader ANU
campus. That’s what I want us to be famous for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-you-really-get-asked-these-questions-frequently-ben&quot;&gt;Do you really get asked these questions &lt;em&gt;frequently&lt;/em&gt;, Ben?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-is-it-really-fair-to-call-it-an-faq&quot;&gt;So is it really fair to call it an &lt;em&gt;F&lt;/em&gt;AQ?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably not. Sorry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:faq&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;At least it’s not a haiku. Or a limerick. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:faq&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:art&quot;&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;Defining “art” is beyond the scope of this blog post, obviously. But I don’t
just mean it in the narrow “high/fine art” sense, although I don’t mean it
in the “all the humanities” sense either. Think making music, drawing
pictures, writing stories—but with an element of technology in the mix. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:art&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:dna&quot;&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;You could even say “weaving it into the College’s DNA”. But that’d be dumb.
Institutions don’t have DNA… except maybe
&lt;a href=&quot;https://biology.anu.edu.au&quot;&gt;RSB&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:dna&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:genevieve&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I’d love to get &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/feraldata&quot;&gt;Genevieve&lt;/a&gt; to write &amp;amp; teach that one. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:genevieve&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:every-course&quot;&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;I kindof want to wriggle out and say &lt;em&gt;most courses&lt;/em&gt;, but I also really want
to see what an artistic submission in lieu of a final exam looks like for
&lt;a href=&quot;https://cs.anu.edu.au/courses/comp3600/&quot;&gt;COMP3600&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:every-course&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:creatives&quot;&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;Although I reject the Romantic notion that “creatives” are some sort of
rarefied “other”, conduits to some deep wellspring of hidden creative mojo
from the other side. We’re all just humans, constructing and engaging in
cultural practices with this stuff, building on what went before. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:creatives&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Swift</name></author><category term="teaching" /><category term="research" /><category term="reimagine" /><summary type="html">The ANU College of Engineering and Computer Science (CECS) is being Reimagined. Don’t take my word for it; listen to our fearless leader Elanor:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Class discussions on Discourse</title><link href="https://benswift.me/blog/2019/02/06/class-discussions-on-discourse/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Class discussions on Discourse" /><published>2019-02-06T19:42:03+11:00</published><updated>2019-02-06T19:42:03+11:00</updated><id>https://benswift.me/blog/2019/02/06/class-discussions-on-discourse</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://benswift.me/blog/2019/02/06/class-discussions-on-discourse/">&lt;p&gt;In 2018 I (with the support of the Teaching &amp;amp; Learning IT team in &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs.anu.edu.au&quot;&gt;my
School&lt;/a&gt;) switched from &lt;a href=&quot;https://piazza.com&quot;&gt;Piazza&lt;/a&gt; to a
self-hosted &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.discourse.org&quot;&gt;Discourse&lt;/a&gt; instance for class
discussions. Specifically, I used it for &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs.anu.edu.au/courses/comp1720/&quot;&gt;COMP1720: Art &amp;amp; Interaction in New
Media&lt;/a&gt;, a large-ish (~200 students)
introductory code/art programming and interaction design course. This course is
open to both CS and non-CS students, and can be counted towards a major in both
the CS and the ANU School of Art and Design.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:artgit&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:artgit&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wasn’t because Piazza sucks—it’s actually pretty great in lots of ways.
But there were a few things we hoped to that Discourse would do better:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;integration with the rest of our class management infrastructure (so that the
professor doesn’t have to keep adding/students manually as enrolment grows
and then settles down at the start of semester)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.discourse.org&quot;&gt;proper API&lt;/a&gt;, rather than using one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hfaran/piazza-api&quot;&gt;unofficial
Piazza API clients&lt;/a&gt; and hoping that
Piazza didn’t break things just before an assigment/exam&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;proper markdown support (with the ability to add whichever programming
languages we like through &lt;a href=&quot;https://highlightjs.org&quot;&gt;highlight.js&lt;/a&gt;
integration) rather than whatever they call the nonsense pseudo-markdown and
flaky rich text editor that Piazza offers&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;self-hosting and controlling where the data is stored, because I don’t think
I ever figured out whether it was technically ok to store student data on a
foreign server and compel students to create an account on same&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.discourse.org/plugins&quot;&gt;plugin ecosystem&lt;/a&gt; so that we could
tweak it to suit our specific needs (and potentially develop our own plugins)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, there are a couple of things that Discourse is missing out-of-the-box
compared to Piazza:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;the ability for instructors (professors &amp;amp; tutors) to mark a question/answer
as a &lt;em&gt;good question/answer&lt;/em&gt; (really handy in teaching)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;the ability for students to “post anonymously to other students” while still
being visible (identifiable) to the instructors&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;ability for students to “accept” an answer,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com&quot;&gt;SO&lt;/a&gt;-style (there’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/discourse/discourse-solved&quot;&gt;plugin for
this&lt;/a&gt;, but we didn’t use it
first time around)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-howd-it-go&quot;&gt;So how’d it go?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty well—student engagement was higher than the previous year (with Piazza)
and anecdotal feedback was that the students liked it. The limitations described
above didn’t bite &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; hard, although I do think that the “post anonymously to
students” thing in particular does encourage students to speak up when they’re
struggling in a way that they don’t when their name is attached to everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the way, we also made some decisions about how to organise/administer a
Discourse server for use as a course forum. Since Discourse isn’t specifically
designed for this task, we had to make a few choices, and it’s worth laying them
out here in case anyone else is going down the same path. Note, you’ll need to
get your head around the Discourse nomenclature if you’re going to use it, but
the crash course is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;threads are called &lt;strong&gt;topics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;topics are grouped into &lt;strong&gt;categories&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;subcategories&lt;/strong&gt; (but only 2
levels max—no &lt;strong&gt;subsubcategories&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;groups&lt;/strong&gt; are groups of users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the way we organised it was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;each course is a &lt;strong&gt;category&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;subcategories&lt;/strong&gt; were devoted to e.g. lectures, labs, assignments, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;access control&lt;/em&gt;: all students were enrolled into a &lt;strong&gt;group&lt;/strong&gt;, which was given
read/write access to the &lt;strong&gt;category&lt;/strong&gt; with the same name&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:samename&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:samename&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tutors (TAs) were given&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example: for COMP1720 we set up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a top-level &lt;em&gt;comp1720&lt;/em&gt; category&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a &lt;em&gt;comp1720&lt;/em&gt; group (in which all students in the course were automatically
enrolled using the Discourse API)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;all tutors are members of a &lt;em&gt;comp1720-tutors&lt;/em&gt; group, which has a higher
privilege level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way, if a student is enrolled in multiple courses, they’ll appear in
multiple groups. They’ll have access to all the topics in the categories for
their courses, but not any topics from other course (of course).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One final bonus is that the default “homepage” for a logged in user shows the
latest posts across all the user’s categories (although users can customise this
behaviour).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got a student who’s working hard to develop a new plugin to restore the
“anon to students, visible to instructors” behaviour, since that’s a
deal-breaker for a lot of folks (it nearly was for me as well). We’ll release
that plugin when it’s done and the kinks are worked out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are still things to figure out as well, but things are looking good. I
wouldn’t go back; I think it’s easier to add the things I miss from Piazza to
Discourse than the other way around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve got experience with this sort of thing and have suggestions or
comments, then get in touch (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/benswift&quot;&gt;@benswift&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ben.swift@anu.edu.au&quot;&gt;ben.swift@anu.edu.au&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:artgit&quot;&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;I also teach all the artists &amp;amp; designers to use git—and it works really
well… with the appropriate scaffolding. Knowing how to use version control
really does feel like having superpowers when editing digital, and seeing
artists and designers realise this is pretty cool. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:artgit&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:samename&quot;&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;the course category (list of topics) and group (list of members) could in
principle have different names &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:samename&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Swift</name></author><category term="teaching" /><category term="web" /><summary type="html">In 2018 I (with the support of the Teaching &amp;amp; Learning IT team in my School) switched from Piazza to a self-hosted Discourse instance for class discussions. Specifically, I used it for COMP1720: Art &amp;amp; Interaction in New Media, a large-ish (~200 students) introductory code/art programming and interaction design course. This course is open to both CS and non-CS students, and can be counted towards a major in both the CS and the ANU School of Art and Design.[^artgit]</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On livecoding annotations and visualisations</title><link href="https://benswift.me/blog/2019/01/31/on-livecoding-annotations-and-visualisations/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On livecoding annotations and visualisations" /><published>2019-01-31T09:53:00+11:00</published><updated>2019-01-31T09:53:00+11:00</updated><id>https://benswift.me/blog/2019/01/31/on-livecoding-annotations-and-visualisations</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://benswift.me/blog/2019/01/31/on-livecoding-annotations-and-visualisations/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve just finished reading Charlie Roberts’ &lt;a href=&quot;https://charlieroberts.github.io/annotationsAndVisualizations/&quot;&gt;interactive web essay on
annotations and visualisations for live
code&lt;/a&gt;. If you
haven’t read it, go do that now—and make sure you have some
speakers/headphones to listen to the code examples, because it would be a real
shame to read it without watching/listening to his ideas in action. All the code
samples (with the visual annotations) are live-editable, both running “whole
blocks” and re-evaluating individual expressions with &lt;code&gt;ctrl+enter&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The essay lays out some guiding principles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There are three principles that guide the design of the presented annotations
and visualizations.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;If a value changes over time (typically related to musical progression or
signal processing), display its current state, either by adding a
visualization / annotation or by modifying the source code to reflect the
current value.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Make annotations and visualizations as proximal as possible to the code
fragment responsible for generating the data they are representing.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;In addition to displaying when values change, whenever possible also provide
some indication of when a value is being read, in particular when there is a
direct affect on musical / sonic output.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It then goes on to show some example visualisation in
&lt;a href=&quot;http://gibberwocky.cc/&quot;&gt;gibberwocky&lt;/a&gt;, both in an “all in” demo and then in
bite-sized listings which show off the different specific ideas. In general, I
really like the ideas, and it’s something Andrew Sorensen and I have written
about before in our paper &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1109/LIVE.2013.6617345&quot;&gt;Visual Code Annotations for Cyberphysical
Programming&lt;/a&gt; (2013) in the &lt;em&gt;1st
International Workshop on Live Programming (LIVE)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:preprint&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:preprint&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (it’s reference
#4 in the essay). I’ll refer to this a bit in this post, so let’s call it “the
LIVE paper”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also think that the three points listed above are pretty solid, especially in
a multimedia livecoding context (maybe even in a broader context). One thing I
like about the visual annotations provided is that they’re mostly ASCII (or
ASCII-ish). This is not so important when deploying them in the web browser
(since you can do so much fancy styling stuff with CSS &amp;amp; js these days) but it’s
really important when dealing with… &lt;em&gt;ahem&lt;/em&gt;, more venerable editors. I ended up
having to use some unholy Emacs hacks with
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/html_node/elisp/Overlays.html&quot;&gt;overlays&lt;/a&gt;
to get the original annotations discussed in the LIVE paper working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that displaying hidden state in comments is a good compromise, and
avoids the need for fancy “extra-textual” overlays. Not that overlays aren’t
sometimes useful, but there’s a lot you can show with inline &lt;code&gt;text-decoration&lt;/code&gt;
hacks and adding a few comments to provide ascii text to decorate (when it isn’t
explicitly represented in the first place).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mixing-annotations-and-live-edits&quot;&gt;Mixing annotations and live edits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But&lt;/strong&gt;, (you can probably tell that there was going to be a “but” somewhere)
many of the cool annotations displayed don’t work while the code is being
edited&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:broken&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:broken&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. In some cases they actually break the code (try editing one of
the &lt;code&gt;'x*ox*xo--x*x*o'&lt;/code&gt; patterns while the code’s running—you’ll end up with
new stuff in your pattern that you didn’t put there).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem isn’t so obvious when all the code listings are fully-formed on page
load, and you can just play them as is. But when you try and mess with the code
then you’ll see what I mean (again, I really suggest that you try it—it’s
super-cool being able to mess around with the live code in the browser).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel this particularly keenly because I’m a clean-slate livecoder (as is
Charlie), so I’m &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; moving through an incomplete code state until I get
something which will even run. This isn’t just a problem for clean-slate
livecoding, though—even tweaks to existing code which introduce “bad” code
states (from the visualisation’s perspective) will cause these issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked about this in the LIVE paper—the fact that there’s a distinction
between the “state of the world” vs “state of the code”. This is a fundamental
challenge for the sorts of inline code visualisation/annotations shown in the
essay, because it’s using the &lt;strong&gt;code&lt;/strong&gt; as the “raw material” for displaying
information about the &lt;strong&gt;world&lt;/strong&gt; (beat/timing and other “hidden variables”, audio
engine state and output, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few different ways to tackle this problem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mark some annotations as “safe” for code being edited, and some “unsafe”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;when code is being edited, turn off all annotations (or at least for that
expression)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;some sort of “grand unified theory” of the delta between the current code
state and the current execution state, and reconcile these to provide a
maximal set of acceptable visualisations (this approach includes a
&lt;a href=&quot;https://coq.inria.fr/&quot;&gt;coq&lt;/a&gt; program to formally verify that you’re doing
everything right)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the pragmatic choice is #2, as long as the “disabled edits” section is
kept as small as possible. It’s still going to be a pain, though, because when
I’m livecoding I’m tweaking stuff all the time, so it’s likely that a lot of the
code will spend a lot of the time with the visualisations disabled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll leave #3 up to people smarter than me 😁 (although perhaps there are
heuristics which could do a decent job).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I can identify with Charlie when he writes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But, in the end, the feedback provided by these annotations and visualizations
have become a critical part of my live coding practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get this—in my experience (when I’ve had even more limited annotations than
the ones he shows in the essay) are just as much for my benefit as the audience.
Livecoding is hard, and any extra information you can get about what’s going on
with your code is super helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In principle visual code annotations can be even more useful to the livecoder
because they allow her to “audition” algorithmic changes to the code
without&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:feedback&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:feedback&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; actually eval-ing the code and changing the music. Here’s an
example from the essay:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;Euclid(9, 16); /* 1010110101011010 */
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might not always know what the &lt;code&gt;9,6&lt;/code&gt; euclidean rhythm is, but I’m by now
fairly used to looking at &lt;code&gt;10100010&lt;/code&gt; sequences and “hearing” the rhythm in my
head. I could poke around with the parameters in a live set, exploring the
parameter space (and thinking through the effect it’ll have on the music) and
then only evaluating the code when I’m satisfied. That’s super powerful—the
equivalent of the DJ cueing the next track with one can on their ear, and one
ear in the club—something which I don’t have currently in my livecoding setup
(although others might).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can probably tell that I think there’s a productive research agenda
here—and I hope Charlie continues with it. I hope to help out myself, too. I
guess my main point is just to shout from the rooftops:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;any code visualisation/annotation techniques must be robust for &lt;strong&gt;code which is
currently being edited&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not just talking about technical issues, either; obviously any
demo/prototype is going to have those, but they’re fixable. I think there are
deeper issues with trying to use &lt;em&gt;live&lt;/em&gt; text as both the description of program
behaviour and as a “view” on the hidden state of the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this is just a blog post, so I’m off the hook with regard to rigour,
accountability and just general good scholarship, right 😜&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;addendum-thoughts-on-web-publishing&quot;&gt;Addendum: thoughts on web publishing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love that this essay/paper is published online—the interactive examples are
crucial to getting the point across. I know that some conferences &amp;amp; journals
these days allow html submission (nicer for reading on mobile, anyway) and other
multimedia artefacts (audio/video recordings) but it’s still hard to get
traction for this sort of rich, interactive in-browser work. The fact that at
the end Charlie has to say:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you’re going to cite this website in an academic paper, please consider
also citing either reference #1 or reference #7 given above; citations of such
papers count more in academia than citations of a website. Plus, there’s
further information in them not covered in this essay. Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh well. Mad props to Charlie for putting this out there for comment and
discussion, and hopefully there are a new generation of publications&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:distill&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:distill&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
where this stuff can be front-and-centre, not just a weird “supplemental web
materials” section to a traditional pdf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:preprint&quot;&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;if you don’t have institutional access to the IEEE then just &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ben.swift@anu.edu.au&quot;&gt;email
me&lt;/a&gt; and I can send you a pre-print. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:preprint&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:broken&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Charlie, if I’m doing it wrong, please let me know :) &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:broken&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:feedback&quot;&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;Yes, I know that the real-time feedback of hearing the sound is crucial, and
I’m not for a second saying that we do away with it, but there are some
situations where I want to check what the result of an algorithmic/parameter
change might be without inflicting it on the audience. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:feedback&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:distill&quot;&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://distill.pub/&quot;&gt;Distill&lt;/a&gt; is great, but it’s pretty DL/AI-focussed.
The livecoding community needs something similar (although it does
privilege livecoding environments which work in the brower, so that’s not
ideal either. Hmm.) &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:distill&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Swift</name></author><category term="livecoding" /><summary type="html">I’ve just finished reading Charlie Roberts’ interactive web essay on annotations and visualisations for live code. If you haven’t read it, go do that now—and make sure you have some speakers/headphones to listen to the code examples, because it would be a real shame to read it without watching/listening to his ideas in action. All the code samples (with the visual annotations) are live-editable, both running “whole blocks” and re-evaluating individual expressions with ctrl+enter.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Oils from 威海</title><link href="https://benswift.me/blog/2019/01/29/oils-from-weihai/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oils from 威海" /><published>2019-01-29T12:24:00+11:00</published><updated>2019-01-29T12:24:00+11:00</updated><id>https://benswift.me/blog/2019/01/29/oils-from-weihai</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://benswift.me/blog/2019/01/29/oils-from-weihai/">&lt;p&gt;One of my academic responsibilities is teaching our ANU Computer Science
programs into our various partner institutions overseas. One of these partner
institutions is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wh.sdu.edu.cn/enDefault.html&quot;&gt;Shandong University
WeiHai&lt;/a&gt; (SDUW).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my trip to SDUW in May 2016, I was walking across the campus one bright
spring morning when I was stopped by a professor from the SDUW School of Art.
Through his limited English and my much more limited Mandarin, he told me that
he wanted me to sit for a portrait session for his first-year painting class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a marathon 4hr sitting&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:tired&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:tired&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, here’s what the students came up with. As
a bonus, I got to choose my favourite one and bring it home—can you guess
which one I chose?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;loop of the finished oil paintings&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/ben-oils-2779bf43241a5e7aa0720d0e7c1f317c057eeeb707014cfdc09c88362aa31e67.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s now hanging on my wall at home, creepily looking down at my family and our
guests. &lt;strong&gt;I love it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:tired&quot;&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;that’s why I look so sullen—I smiled no-stop for the first hour (when they
were painting the background) but by the time they were putting on the
facial details 3hrs in I was &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; too tired to keep my smile up 😊 &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:tired&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Swift</name></author><category term="teaching" /><summary type="html">One of my academic responsibilities is teaching our ANU Computer Science programs into our various partner institutions overseas. One of these partner institutions is Shandong University WeiHai (SDUW).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Old livecoding photo roundup</title><link href="https://benswift.me/blog/2019/01/22/old-livecoding-photo-roundup/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Old livecoding photo roundup" /><published>2019-01-22T13:12:00+11:00</published><updated>2019-01-22T13:12:00+11:00</updated><id>https://benswift.me/blog/2019/01/22/old-livecoding-photo-roundup</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://benswift.me/blog/2019/01/22/old-livecoding-photo-roundup/">&lt;p&gt;I’m trying to find all the photos of me doing livecoding gigs over the past 10
years. If you’ve got an old photo of me doing my thing, then can you either
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ben.swift@anu.edu.au&quot;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/benswift&quot;&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt; at
me to share it? I’ll give you authoreal credit and hugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any photos of actual gigs, they’ll go into the
&lt;a href=&quot;/livecoding/index.html&quot;&gt;livecoding&lt;/a&gt; section of this website.
However, I also do lots of other presentations, talks and demos which don’t
really count as “gigs”. For those, I’ll just add the photos here as they turn
up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;australian-council-of-deans-of-ict-2017&quot;&gt;Australian Council of Deans of ICT 2017&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Ben livecoding at the Council of Deans' of ICT meeting&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/livecoding/ben-alta-f65b59efe5c97c2c50367987698a0962cfa684f4252cc34cfbbf6673ade06115.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/FalknerKatrina/status/854861227809361920&quot;&gt;@FalknerKatrina&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;australian-institute-of-physics-congress-2014&quot;&gt;Australian Institute of Physics Congress 2014&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Ben livecoding a physics simulation at AIP congress&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/livecoding/ben-AIP-congress-53c24a4daa26112790b1c8feef98c5ff50f2800f1444dbae9e3cf0511304db0a.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/starstoofondly/status/542177320321024000&quot;&gt;@starstoofondly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;australasian-computer-music-conference-acmc-2007&quot;&gt;Australasian Computer Music Conference (ACMC) 2007&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;ACMC attendees hanging out at Kremlin bar&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/livecoding/ben-acmc-07-kremlin-014fc7330592130a587ae8910ca57d941b4ca3cd74f1e7c6758660156783c556.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t me &lt;em&gt;performing&lt;/em&gt;, unless you count my animated conversation with
Gordon Monro as a performance.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Swift</name></author><category term="gigs" /><category term="livecoding" /><summary type="html">I’m trying to find all the photos of me doing livecoding gigs over the past 10 years. If you’ve got an old photo of me doing my thing, then can you either email or tweet at me to share it? I’ll give you authoreal credit and hugs.</summary></entry></feed>